# Nicholas Weber

## Front-End Web Developer & UX Designer

nikkoweber@icloud.com · (763)-218-5996 · nikkoweber.com

## **Professional Summary**

More than three years of experience as both a designer and developer of corporate websites. Have numerous achievements under my belt, including the complete design and development of a corporate website (100+ pages including an eCommerce system) from scratch. Experience with both traditional web markup and content management systems; able to adaptably use both with proficiency.

Extensive experience with WordPress, including custom theming, building sites with Elementor, and using plugins. Can build new sites in WordPress as well as traditional web markup with quick turnaround, including sites with advanced front-end functionality.

#### **Education**

Capella University (2018-2019)

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology Minor in Web Application Development

#### **Experience**

#### Web Developer Intern

Lube-Tech, Golden Valley, MN / Jan 2016 - Feb 2020

- · Was paid to learn WordPress fundamentals and custom theming
- Learned Git, DNS, and SFTP
- Designed the company website (100+ pages) from scratch
- · Developed the new company website in Angular
- Designed and implemented the UI for the eCommerce system
- Made modifications and additions to the website over time

#### Web Developer

TravelNet Solutions, Cottage Grove, MN / Feb 2020 - Mar 2020

- Developed web content in the WordPress theme Avada
- Implemented web content for various clients
- Created modifications to the existing web content
- Laid off due to COVID-19's impact on the hospitality industry

#### Consultation

Various / Mar 2020 - Present

- Assisted in development of websites in applications
  - Helped my father with front-end/UI considerations for personal and work projects
  - $\circ$  Helped my girlfriend's mother with a website for a nonprofit
    - Learned about many plugins including Elementor

## **Professional Skills**

- General skills
  - o Front-end web design & development
  - User experience design
  - Responsive design & development
  - o Git
  - o Command line
  - o PhotoShop
  - Prototyping
    - Adobe XD
  - o DNS
  - FTP/SFTP
- Web markup
  - HTML5
  - o CSS
  - o SASS
  - Bootstrap 4
  - HTML email developments
  - WordPress
    - Theme development
    - Divi builder
    - Elementor
    - A multitude of plugins
- Scripting
  - JavaScript
  - JavaScript DOM manipulation
  - o Angular 2+
    - Angular Material
- Soft skills
  - o Personability
  - Critical analysis
  - o Problem solving
  - Working effectively in teams